소등 5분 전
Five minutes.
프랭크 어딨어?
Where's Frank?
레니 드레이크
8년형
Lenny DRAKE 8 YEARS.
비브 바티스타
12년형
VIV Batista 12 YEARS.
브로디
종신형
Brodie LIFELONG.
제임스 레시
7년형
JAMES Lacey 7 YEARS.
좋은 친구 둔거야
You just got yourself a friend.
돈 걸어
Your bets.
병신 한마리가 있다
다리 한쪽이 없어
He's a handicap,
fool's missing a leg.
- 붉은 놈한테 두장
- 늦었어, 이미 출발했어
Am good for two on red.
Too late, Frank. The riders are on the track.
- 그럼 돌려줘
- 미안, 빚진 거 있지?
Then give it back.
Sorry, Frank.
You owe the bank.
- 이감돼?
- 출소야, 프랭크
Transfer?
- Am out, Frank.
그냥 그렇게?
Just like that?
잘 있어
Bye.
헷지는요?
Where's Hedge?
못 봤나?
방금 나갔잖아
Did not see him?
He's out the door.
- 그래요?
- 다음이 자네 차례야
Is he?
- You're next, Lenny.
위원들이 잘 봐줬으니
너도 유리할거야
If they are soft on him,
then things are good for you.
이제 와서 파트너쉽을
깨뜨리진 않겠지?
May be its not like that.
They don't have spilt off such a formidable
partnership now, is it?
드레이크
Drake.
이거 놔, 놓으라고!
Get your fucking hands off me.
헷지!
Hedges.
통로로 모여!
Catwalk.
안녕, 형
Hello, Brother.
- 말 좀 해봐
- 너 약 빨았지?
Come on, let it out.
- You've smoked.
한 놈만 주라
형이 왕이잖아
Give me one. Come on.
You have all of them.
- 너 약 주는 놈 있어?
- 절대로 없어
Someone takes care of you?
- Of course not.
- 확실해?
- 응, 한놈만 주라
Are you sure?
- Yes, I want one of that pussies.
제발, 제발
한 놈만...
Come on, come on.
Give me one.
애송이들!
Pussies.
야, 너!
귀엽게 생겼네
Hey, you.
Have a good look.
다음에 날 보면
벽에 붙어 있어라!
The next time I see you
are you with your face against the wall.
- 벽에 대고!
- 당연하지
Against the wall, Yes.
- You bet.
애송이, 애송이, 애송이들!
Pussies. Pussies. Pussies.
애송이, 애송이, 애송이들아!
여기가 네 감방,
네 침대, 감방 동료
This is your cell. This is your bunk.
This is your cellmate.
제임스 레시예요
James Lacey.
페리, 편지다
Perry. Mail.
반송
RETURN TO SENDER.
프랭크 페리,
죄수번호 23401
Frank Perry, Prisoner Number 23401.
딴 데 쳐다봐
Is there somewhere else.
내 생각하지, 애송아?
You thinking about me, Pussy?
난 다 알아
I know you are.
죄수 24484 브로디,
감방에 없음
Prisoner 24484 Brodie, absent from cell.
죄수 27103 레시,
감방에 없음
Prisoner 27103 Lacey, absent from cell.
죄수 23410 페리,
감방에 없음
Prisoner 23410 Perry, absent from cell.
- Prisoner 26432 Drake, absent from cell.
죄수 26432 드레이크
감방에 없음
죄수 135 바티스타,
Prisoner 135 Batista, absent from cell.
늦게 왔구만
예배실 닫혔어
You come at the wrong time,
the chapel's closed.
페리
Perry.
이봐...
Hey...
시간이 좀 걸릴거야
Its gonna be a while.
밖에서 기다리지
I'll be right outside.
정말 힘드네
This is very hard.
그래도...
But...
딸을 꼭 만나야 해
I just have to see her.
식사 시간이야
바티스타
It's feeding time, Batista.
책
Book.
잡지
Magazine.
카드 좀 줘
Give me a card.
한 장만, 바티스타
Come on, one card, Batista.
한 장만 줘
Just give me one.
이리 내!
Give it to me.
네 형한테나 구걸해
Go back to your brother.
기다릴 줄도 알아야지
Do you get to wait a while.
녀석이 갈수록 건방져!
날 비웃었어!
He's getting cocky.
He's just laughing at me.
나한테 12장이나
빚졌어 12장을!
He owe me a dozen.
He owe me a fucking dozen.
말이 많다, 나가
Get out.
You are overtalking now. Get out.
바티스타
Batista.
따라와
Come with me.
네가 선택해
Your choice.
토니가 부탁...
Tony said...
토니...
Tony...
장군
Checkmate.
11년만에 처음 졌네
Its the first time in 11 years.
한판 더, 프랭크?
Another game, Frank?
레시, 산책하다 와
Lacey, have a wander.
- 가기 싫은데요
- 산책하다 와
Am not really in the mood.
- Have a wander.
이리 와
Come on.
5분만
Five minutes.
뭐?
What?
세탁실 환기구
The air vents in the laundry.
하수구와 연결됐지
않겠어?
Would they connect to the sewer?
- 뭐라고?
- 건조기 뒤에
Come again?
- The back of the dryers.
하수구와 연결돼있잖아?
Would they connect to
the sewerage system?
프랭크, 무슨 일이야?
Frank, what's going on?
14년만에 받은
첫 편지야
My first letter in 14 years.
내 딸내미가 중독자래
Telling me my little girl is a junkie.
심장이 2번이나 멈췄대
Her heart stopped twice.
- 걘 그럴...
- 아니!
She is not...
- No.
심장이 다시
멈추기 전에...
Before that happens again...
만나야 해
I gotta see her.
- 일을 바로잡을거야
- 프랭크
I have to make things right.
- Frank.
나가고 싶어, 브로디
I want out, Brodie.
1개월도 아니고,
6개월도 안 돼
Not in a month,
not six.
지금 당장
Now.
세탁실 환기구가
연결됐지?
The air vents in the laundry,
do they connect?
프랭크, 난 몰라...
Frank, I got nothing...
다신 묻지 않겠어
연결됐지?
Do they connect?
Am not asking again.
그래
Yeah.
헌데... 환기구가 막혔어
철판은 못 뚫어
But the air vents... it will be capped.
You won't get through solid steel.
- 드레이크는 가능해
- 드레이크? 곧 나갈...
Lenny Drake can.
- Lenny Drake? He's walking off...
가석방 거부됐어
헷지가 밀고후 먼저 나갔거든
His parol's been revoked.
Hedges grassed him for an early release.
환기구 뚜껑을 지나도
Suppose you get past the caps.
환기구가 경계선
밖까지 나진 않아
The vent won't take you
as far to the perimeter.
나오면 바로 잡힐걸
once surfaced you will be picked off.
그래서 깊이
들어가려는 거지
That's why i will go deeper.
- 싫어, 다신 안 돌아가
- 넌 안 가도 돼
No, am not going back down there.
- Am telling you. You don't have to.
- 프랭크, 내가 왜...
- 닥치고 들을래?
Jesus, Frank. You know why I'm in this..
- Would you listen?
- 알려만 달라는 거야
- 말 못해줘
I want you to tell me not pick me.
- I can't tell you.
빌어먹을!
Fuck.
난 지도 못 그려줘
I cannot even draw a map.
정말로 할 계획이야?
Are you sure of your case?
프랭크
Frank.
나 없인 길을
잃을 거야
Without me, you will be lost in minutes.
딴데 좀 봐주실래요?
Stare at someone else.
- 말할 기분 아녜요
- 그 기분 잘 알지
I am not in the mood for a chat. OK.
- I can understand that.
날 밀고했어요
Cunt, snitched me off.
말하자면 내가
가장 많이 놀랐어
But i tell you, nobody
was more surprised than i was.
놈은 유유히 나가고
난 고메즈랑 뺑이만 쳤고
He walks it and i gets nailed for Gomez.
빡쳐서 경비 죽이고
헷지 녀석은 도망쳤어요
So i murdered a guard,
Hedges.. fucker was holding him down.
나가면 그 놈을...
When I walk outta that door...
내보내줄 수 있다면
어떡할래, 레니?
Suppose I can get you
outta the door.. Lenny?
닥쳐요, 말할 기분
아니랬잖아요
Fuck with it, OK.
I told you, I am not in the mood.
뭐가 좋을까?
허구하게 주머니 치기?
What would you prefer to
smack up a little harder...
아님 2인자 패버리기?
on your number two?
패버려?
Smack?
훨씬 더 잔인하게
다뤄줄 거예요
I have something more brutal in mind.
자네가 벽을 뚫어주면
매우 유용할텐데
You walk through walls, Lenny.
And thats useful.
그래요?
Is it?
얘기하는 척만 해
관심 안 받게
Say we talk,
and you're not interested.
내 말대로 해줘
이 얘긴 비밀이야
Well, it goes as it sound.
We never talked.
좋아요
해 드리죠
Yeah.
도미노
Domino.
참가자는 셋
Three players.
좋아요
장애물은?
Alrite.
Barriers?
하나
One.
둘
Two.
셋
Three.
- 자물쇠는?
- 연장과 열쇠
Locks?
- Pumps and keys.
불가능해요
No chance.
난 도둑이지
마법사가 아녜요
I am a thief, not magician.
- 다른 길이 있어
- 무슨 길?
There is another way.
- How?
샤워실 배수구야
The shower drain.
세탁실 바로 위야
Directly above.
거기도 다를 바 없어
또 벽이 있잖아
The same problem above.
And more barriers.
딱 한개야
예배실 벽이지
Only one. The Chapel wall.
- 밤새 뚫어야 할텐데
- 고해성사를 해봤나?
It will take all night.
- Ever considered confession?
고해성사실 안의
벽 판자가 헐거워...
Back of the confession wall,
panels... loose.
예배실 문은?
And the Chapel door?
연장은?
What about tools?
주님이...
The Lord...
제공하신다
.. provides.
도미노
Domino.
제시간에 가면
나사가 풀릴 거예요
First time...,
screws will come running.
- 경보가 울릴텐데
- 누가 세팅하지?
Alarms will be inevitable.
- Who sets that out? - We.
우리가
십자가가 사라진걸
알아챌 때
When they find Holy Cross missing.
- It is an obstacle course. - It is.
- 그것도 문제잖아요
- 맞아
경비들이 처음부터
알았다고 치면...
If they are on to us from the off...
경보가 울릴때쯤
우린 배수구에...
We will over the drains
when the alarm goes.
경비들이 이렇게
멀어졌을 때...
By the time that they leave this far...
우린 세탁실에 있겠지
.. we will be in the laundry.
경비들이 세탁실까지
얼마나 걸리지?
How long we got before
they are in the laundry?
최대 5분
Five minutes.
Tops.
그거면 충분해
Its enough.
좋아
Alrite.
다음 단계는
건조기
Next piece.
The dryer.
- 자물쇠는?
- 나보다도 오래됐어
Locks?
- Older than me.
환풍기 커버는?
What about the cover on the vents?
그건 걱정하지 마요
You don't worry about that.
- 내가 뚫어낼테니
- 아니, 걱정돼
I will sever them in.
- Yeah, I do worry.
강철 자를 수 있는
물건 있어?
Have you got something
that cuts through steel?
내가 어떻게든 할거요
Am over everything's.
5분만 얘기하지, 2톤
Five minutes of your time, Two Ton?
내가 싸울 상대를
골라놨는데
I think, i may have found you a challenger.
도미노
Domino.
안에 들어가면
숨만 쉬어, 말은 금지야
From the minute we are inside,
you breathe.. you do not talk.
지하에선
메아리가 치거든
That far underground.. it echoes.
생각도 금물이야
Ignore you thinking,
it only be playing tricks.
지하에선
모든 게 달라져
Things are different down there.
세탁실 환풍구 끝이
집수공 꼭대기야
The laundry vents will take us here
top of the sump.
그 후엔 더 내려가지
Then we go deep.
내려가면
하수 터널이 있어
Its a drainage tunnel.
거길 통과해야 하고
그 다음엔...
Now we gonna need to get through that.
After that...
여기쯤에
강이 있어
This far,
its the river.
- 무슨 강?
- 남쪽에 있는 강, 알지?
What river?
- We are South, remember?
난 수영 못하는데
I can't swim.
못해?
강 깊숙히 들어갈텐데
No?
We go under it.
둑 아래
빈 공간이 있는데
There is a reservoir
under the embankment.
지하철과 연결돼
Its connects the rail network.
선로에 도달하면
모든 길이 로마로 통해
Once we are on the tracks,
all roads lead to Rome.
바로 위에
'채링 크로스' 역이야
'Charing Cross' Thats where we surface.
왜 멀리 가지?
가까운 역도 많은데
Why so far-off? It got to be stations closer.
- Plenty of reasons.
이유야 많지
- 러시아워에 탈출이 쉽지
- 러시아워 전이여야 해
Easy to disappear with rush hour.
- No, before rush hour.
열차는 새벽 5시에 가동돼
630 볼트나 되지
The tracks goes alive at 5 O'clock.
630 Volts.
그 전에 승강장에
못 가면 춤을 춰야지
If we are not on the platform by then,
we tap-dancing.
어떻게 이런 걸
다 알지?
How do you know all this?
How did he know all this?
12년간 거기서 살았으니까
Because I shivered shit
down there for 12 years.
참 멋진 인생이네요
...for you then.
시간이 얼마나 되죠?
Ok. How much time?
소등 벨이 9시니까
8시간이 주어져
The end bell rings at 9 O'clock.
That gives us eight hours.
- 언제 가지?
- 시간이 얼마나 필요해?
When do we go?
- How much do you need?
사흘요
Three days.
그럼 됐어
Its good for me.
금요일에...
On Friday...
간다
We go.
한가지 더
One more thing:
절대 오늘 밤엔
죽지 마
Just make sure you don't
get murdered tonight.
그럼 그렇지
다윗과 골리앗은 헛소리야
There you go. Proof.
David and Goliath is cock and bullshit.
너무 확신하지 마
Wouldn't be too sure.
뭘 떨어뜨렸나?
Did you drop something?
안 보여
Didn't see that.
안 떨어뜨렸잖아
No, you didn't.
비눗칠 해 드려?
Fancy soap you, Frank?
뭐?
What?
허가 받았어?
You got a mission?
안 받았군
You don't.
엿 먹어
Fuck.
내 형이
가만있을 것 같아?
Fuck.
Thats not gonna make Rizza happy.
이 몸 때문에
곤란해질걸
Trouble is eye for mine now.
네 계획을 망쳐주지
These eyes are...
난 뭐든 할수 있어
일 크게 벌이지 말라구
I could sort some out here.
Avoid any trouble.
뭔데?
What?
어서, 프랭크
도망치지 마
Come on, Frank.
Don't run.
내가 더 빠르거든
I can run faster.
네가 아무데도 못 가게
내 형이 막을 거야
Rizza gets into this to make sure
you don't go anyway.
내 말을 안 들으면
Unless you swear me on.
그래, 맞아
Yeah, that's right.
이제 됐나?
내일 첫 벨이
울릴 때야, 프랭크
First Bell's tomorrow, Frank.
네 감방에서, 프랭크?
In your cell, Frank, yes?
첫 벨이야
First bell.
내려 놔!
Drop it.
이러지 마, 일을
망치게 두지 않겠어!
Don't do this.
I won't let you fuck this up.
식초를 뿌린
'피쉬 앤 칩스' 어때?
'Fish and Chips ' throw in some vinegar?
How about that?
어차피 먹을 텐데
You don't look?
안 그래?
Right?
이런 좋은 날에
기분이 나빠?
Bad,
first day in summer.
잘 다진 신선한 대구...
This large portion of fresh battered cod,
갓 신문지로 싼
wrapped in newspaper.
예쁜 아가씨들이 달려가고
Most beautiful girls jog by...
Do you know what i mean?
뭔 소린지 알겠어?
아니
No.
괜찮아?
You, alrite?
뭔데 그래?
What?
토니
Tony.
- 빌어먹을
- 뭔데요?
Fuck.
- What?
어떻게 알아챘지?
How did the fuck he find out?
- 뭘 요구해?
- 5백 그램
What does he want?
- Half a key.
- 5백 그램? 그정도면...
- 여러가지 방안이 있어
Half a fucking key? Thats bit off a... worth.
- We got alternatives.
그래요, 확 죽여버리죠
Yeah, I suggest the option
that murders him.
걔 형 '리자'때문에
못 건드려
Not if Rizza's on our back.
Not a chance. Tony is untouchable.
토니 말고, 바티스타
마약을 훔쳐요
Not Tony, Batista.
We go in and plunder his stash.
어쩌려고? 우리가...
What do we do now? We go...
침대 아래를 뒤져?
주머니를 뒤져?
look under his mattress?
Check his pockets?
녀석도 수가 있어
다 알아채지 않겠냐고?
Fucker's got a operation going on.
You don't think he's smarter than that?
녀석이 슈퍼맨도
아니잖아요
Prick's not made of fucking kryptonite.
아무도 안 죽여
상대가 토니라도
Nobody's getting their hands bloody
for Tony. Nobody.
- 혼자 해결하게요?
- 아니
Are you covering him?
- No.
그럼?
So?
만약에...
What if...
바티스타도 데려간다면
어떻게 할까?
that ticket out,
is worth something to Batista?
5백 그램?
Half a key?
- 그냥 건네주라고요?
- 아니
And you want me to give it to you?
- No.
거래야
Its a trade.
또 누가 가지?
Who else is going?
브로디
Brodie.
그리고 레니 드레이크
And Lenny Drake.
레니 드레이크?
Lenny Drake?
'CAT' 5백 그램이면
한달이나 걸려요
Half a key of CAT cuts me out for a month.
토니도 알아요
Tony knows that.
그러니까...
어떻게든 만들어 줘야지
So...
Tony's going to taste.
토니는 당신이
날 죽이거나
He thinks, you will kill me for it or steal it.
훔쳐서 뺏을거라
생각해요
잘못돼면 내가 죽겠죠
어떻게든 난 죽어요
Which puts me in a coffin or worse,
if i...
게다가...
Besides...
토니가 알면
토니가 안 거죠
if Tony knows, then Tony knows.
놈이 못 나가게
막을 거예요
He's the devil on your back now.
거래를 원하면
거래를 해 드리죠
But if you wanna trade,
I give a trade.
'CAT'는 중독되면
빠져나오지 못해요
CAT's a dangerous drug.
But deadly when poisoned.
알겠어요?
You got me?
만일 'CAT'와 같이
냄새랑 맛이 같다면...
If it looks,
smells and tastes like CAT...
- 가짠줄 누가 알겠어요?
- 아무도 토니는 못 건드려
Who will know?
- No one touches Tony.
- 리자는...
- 리자?
Rizza..
- Rizza?
누가 리자를 감시하죠?
Who going after Rizza?
약쟁이들은 매일 죽어요
Junkies die every day.
좋아
Alrite.
거래 성사예요
Thats a trade.
젠장
Shit.
브로디, 기다려
Brodie, wait.
브로디...
Brodie...
소등, 소등
Lights Out.
LIGHTS OUT.
담배 피우나?
You smoke?
저게 마지막으로 딸을
봤던 때지
That was the last time that I saw her.
내일이면 21살이야
She will be 21 tomorrow.
그가 밧줄을 잘라
여자를 내려줬네
He took a knife and cut her down.
그녀의 가슴엔
이렇게 써 있었지
And on her boobies, these lines he found:
정말 어리석은 아가씨...
Oh, what a foolish girl...
내게도 정육점집
아들이 있었지
Was i, too had my son for a butcher's boy.
가 내 무덤을 파라
깊고 넓게...
Go dig my grave,
both wide and deep.
내 머리와 발에
대리석을 놓아주게
Put a marble stone at my head and feet.
그리고 내 무덤 위에...
And on my grave...
난 사랑을 위해 죽었네...
...i died for love.
이거 아늑하군
This is cozy.
추워 보이니
담요를 덮어줘야겠어
You should wrap a blanket
around him, Frank.
Its cold.
- 시간 좀 줘
- 안 돼
Give us a moment.
- No.
안돼, 얜 남을거야
No, he stays.
이 녀석이
마음에 들거든
I like his company.
나한테 줄게 있지 않아?
Got something for me or not, Frank.
사익스는 여기서 뭐해?
What Sykes doing here?
마음의 평화를
위해 왔다고 쳐
Call it peace of mind.
입을 다물어줄지
어떻게 알아?
How do I know,
you will keep your mouth shut?
- 산 걸 다행으로 여겨
- 보장이 필요해
You're lucky, you still fucking standing.
- I need a guarantee.
- 더는 안 되지
- 이건 거래라고
What you want?
- Its a trade.
조용히 않겠다면
거래는 없어
I want a guarantee that you will keep
your mouth shut, otherwise no deal.
규칙은 내가 정해
You don't make rules.
그래
Yeah.
다 먹어 치워
Have a burn.
형!
Rizza.
괜찮아, 괜찮아질 거야
It's ok.
It's alrite, kid.
문 열어!
Open the door.
어서, 프랭크
당장!
Do it, Perry.
Now.
프랭크
Frank...
Frank.
- 뭔가 보여
- 뭐요?
I see some.
- What?
놈이 느닷없이 나타났어
He came out of nowhere.
자네가 어쩔 도리가
없었잖아?
You.. You couldn't do a thing?
- 저 녀석은 산송장이야
- 우리도 마찬가지지
Well, he is a walking corspe now.
- We all are.
왜 그래?
죽여줘서 고맙구만
Why?
Nicky did the job for us.
리자가 사익스를 찾아내면
무슨 일인지 알아볼걸?
As soon as he finds Sykes,
Rizza gonna...
현재로선 리자는 몰라요
Rizza's not going.
토니가 뭘 가지러
갔다는 것밖에 모르죠
The only thing he knows,
that Tony took a...
레시는 지금쯤
어떻게 됐을까?
And Lacey What happens to him now?
독방엔 오래있지 못해
He won't there be long.
리자가 나오게 할 거야
Rizza will make sure of that.
레시는 리자 손에
맡겨야지
We will leave him to Rizza.
뭐가 더 무겁죠?
1톤 정도의 벽돌
Which weighs more, Frank:
a ton of bricks...
아니면 1톤 정도의 깃털?
.. or a ton of feathers?
녀석은 어쨋건 죽어
He is a dead man,
whatever ever fights him.
계획대로 내일 떠나죠
So we leave tomorrow,
as planned.
- 어디 가?
- 고해성사를 안 했어요
Where you going?
- Its been a while since my last confession.
내버려 둬
냅두라고
Leave it.
그를 따라가
Follow him.
어서요, 선로 가동까지
1시간 남았어요
Let's move, we got one hour
before the tracks go alive.
들어봐!
Listen.
- 우릴 찾았어!
- 어서 가!
They found us.
- Move.
계속 가!
Keep moving.
안녕하신가, 프랭크
Hi, Frank.
안녕, 리자
Hello, Rizza.
- 동생 일은 유감이야
- 왜, 네가 죽였어?
Am sorry about your brother.
- Why's that? Did you kill him?
- 난 그럴 이유가 없지
- 이유야 항상 있어
I have no reason.
- There is always reasons.
약쟁인데다 미친놈이라
아무도 안 좋아했지
He was a junkie.
He's a cunt, no one liked him.
난 안 피워, 옆에서
피는 것도 싫어하지
I don't smoke, Frank.
Don't like smoke around me.
가족이 있나, 프랭크?
You have a family, Frank?
있어
Yeah.
자식은?
Any young?
정말 예쁜 딸이군
Oh.. she's a gorgeous one.
애를 사랑해?
Do you love her?
가족은 중요한 거야
Family's important.
유일하게 중요한 거지
The only important thing.
한번만 묻겠어
So I will only ask you once.
다신 안 묻겠다
I won't ask again.
토니가 걔를 고문했어
He was torturing the lad.
토니가 그 녀석을
좋아했지
He had a fancy for him.
토니가 문가에서...
Tony was over by the doorway...
녀석을 향해 갔어
.. making moves on him.
사익스가...
Sykes...
토니를 출입구에서
잡아당겼지
.. pulled him from the door way.
다투면서 싸우는
소리를 들었어
I heard them arguing.
Fighting.
1분 후...
After a minute.
모든 게...
잠잠해졌지
The whole... was quiet.
얘기를 많이 빼먹었군...
You have not done much...
- 얘길 돌려말했어
- 리자...
you just distracted from whats left.
- Rizza...
또 거짓말했군
You lie to me one more time...
그 놈을 오늘 밤...
Then bring in your boy out tonight.
소등 전에 데려와
네가 데려오도록 해
I want him in my cell before closing time.
You bring him.
이것만은 알아둬, 프랭크
You got one thing..., Frank.
당신은 죽기엔
너무 늙었어
You're too old to die young.
- 괜찮아요?
- 아니
Are you alrite?
- No.
괜찮구만
He's alrite.
정신 차려요, 프랭크
Stay with us, Frank.
준비됐어?
Are you ready?
페리?
Perry?
바티스타, 미트라,
파크허스트
Batista, Mitra,
Parkhurst.
방문자실로
Visiting Room.
기다려, 프랭크
Wait, Frank.
어서 움직여요
선로가 가동됐어요
Let's move.
It means the tracks are not alive.
프랭크
Frank.
프랭크, 어서 움직여요!
Frank, move now.
도와 줘
Help me.
어서, 가!
Go, go, go.
가!
Go.
움직여!
Move.
앉아
Sit down.
어디서 왔나?
Where are you from, lad?
런던이요
London.
- 올드 스트리트요
- 올드 스트리트?
Old Street.
- Old Street?
내 고향이 어딘지
생각이 안나
I can't remember my street.
리자가 제 방에서
널 기다려
Rizza's waiting for you in his cell.
나더러 널 데려오래
He wants me to take you there.
예배실로 가
Go to the chapel, lad,
소등 벨이
울리기 전에
before the end bell.
고해성사를 하고
이걸 브로디에게 줘
And make your confession.
Give this to Brodie.
- 이해가 안 돼요
- 안 될게 뭐가 있어?
I don't understand.
- Yes, you do.
왜 저죠, 프랭크?
Why me, Frank.
널 보면 내 딸이
생각나거든
You remind me of someone.
소등 5분 전
Five minutes.
놈은 어딨지?
Where is he?
그게 말이지...
You know...
이 책을 12번 읽어야 해
I must have read this book a dozen times.
시간이 나면 처음부터
If I had my time again,
i can start over like..
다시 읽을 거야
.. re-reading this book.
나랑 얘기할 사람이
있다면 얘기해 줬겠지
May there's someone i shud sit down
and talk to. I talk some sense into him.
세상살이가 어떤지
Tell him how things really are.
하지만 못해
But I can't.
그 사람은 이미
죽었거든
That man is long gone,
남은 게 이것뿐이야
and am all thats left
- 그놈 어딨어?
- 그거 알아?
Where is he?
- But you know something?
난 이제 자유야
I am free now.
- 내 딸처럼
- 자유?
Like my little girl.
- Free?
- 상상력이 좋군
- 상상은 우릴 지켜주지
You have got an imagination.
- Imaginations will protect us.
상상이 우릴
살게 해주는 거야
Thats what keeps us alive.
넌 아직 살아있지만
서서히 죽어갈테지
You are still alive,
but less and less.
여기서 넌
이곳의 주인이지만
Inside.. you own this place.
일도 벌이고
You run things,
왕일진 몰라도
둘러봐, 뭐가 보여?
you are the king,
but look around you, what you see?
전부 가짜야
Its all pretend.
전부 다...
Its all...
네겐 아무것도 없어
You own nothing.
이 방과 철창
녹슨 철계단 뿐이지
Nothing except cells, bars,
and a rusty metal staircase.
넌 절대로 못살아
밖에선 네가 존재하지 않듯
You'll never live
because outside you don't exist.
- 넌 잊혀질 거야
- 말조심 해
No one will remember you.
- You behave yourself.
말조심한 덕분에
이렇게까지 살아있는거지
Behaving myself
is whats kept me alive this long.
- 어딨는지 말해
- 레시?
You tell me where he is.
- Lacey?
녀석은 괜찮을 거야
He be alrite.
- 녀석은 떠났어, 리자
- 뭐라고?
He's gone, Rizza.
- What did you say?
갔다고
Gone.
프랭크는 어딨어?
Where is Frank?
그 친구는 자유야
The lad's free.
감히 내게 등을 돌려?
Don't you walk away from me.
네가 말했듯이
Just like you said:
난 너무 늙었어...
I'm too old...
경보 울려!
Alarm.
프랭크...
Frank...
프랭크!
Frank.
I got no air.
브로디...
Brodie...
프랭크
Frank.
- 프랭크
- 프랭크!
Frank.
- Frank.
공기가 없어
There's no air.
숨을 못 쉬겠어
I can't breathe.
어서 숨 쉬어요!
...c'mon breathe.
정신 차려요, 프랭크
Stay with us, Frank.
- 정신 차려요
- 어서, 프랭크
Stay with us.
- Come on, Frank.
어서, 프랭크
Come on, Frank.
Come on.
우린 자유야
We are Free.